
#Quiz Data Collect Already Because this video is very long time are Consume
# All data are Collect to internet.

quiz =[
    {
    "Question":"1.Where did Gandhi use Satyagraha for the first time?",
    "option" :["(A) India",
               "(B) South Africa",
               "(C) South America",
               "(D) England"],
    "answer" : "B"
    },{
    "Question":"2._______ was the moderate leader of Congress",
    "option" :["(A) Lala Lajpat Rai",
               "(B) Bipin Chandra Pal",
               "(C) Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
               "(D) Gopal Krishna Gokhale"
               ],
    "answer" : "D"
    },{
    "Question":"3.Gandhiji took back Non Cooperation movement in __________?",
    "option" :["(A) January 1921",
               "(B) February 1922 ",
               "(C) February 1921 ",
               "(D) January 1922"
               ],
    "answer" : "B"
    },{
    "Question":"4. Peasant Satyagraha at Bardoli was hold in ___________?",
    "option" :["(A)  1928",
               "(B)  1929",
               "(C)  1930",
               "(D)  1931"],
    "answer" : "A"
    },{
    "Question":"5.Congress Ministries resigned in _________?",
    "option" :["(A) Oct. 1937",
               "(B) Sept. 1938",
               "(C) Sept. 1940",
               "(D) Oct. 1939"
               ],
    "answer" : "D"
    },{
    "Question":"6.Which of the following was not a member of SEATO?",
    "option" :["(A) U.S.S.R.",
               "(B) New Zealand",
               "(C) Pakistan",
               "(D) Australia"
               ],
    "answer" : "A"
    },{
    "Question":"7.Here is a list of countries. Write against each of these the bloc they belonged to during the Cold War.?",
    "option" :["(A) Poland",
               "(B) France",
               "(C) Nigeria",
               "(D) Sri Lanka"],
    "answer" : "A"
    },{
    "Question":"8.Which among the following statements does not reflect the objectives of NAM?",
    "option" :["(A)  Enabling newly decolonized countries to pursue independent policies.",
               "(B) Not to joining any military alliances.",
               "(C) Following a policy of neutrality on global issues.",
               "(D)  Focus on elimination of global economic inequalities."],
    "answer" : "C"
    },{
    "Question":"9.Which among the following statements about the Cold War is wrong ?",
    "option" :["(A) It was a competition between the US and Soviet Union and their respective allies",
               "(B) It was an ideological war between the superpowers",
               "(C) It triggered of an arms race",
               "(D) The US and U.S.S.R. were engaged in direct wars"],
    "answer" : "D"
    },{
    "Question":"10.Which of the following was not a member of NATO?",
    "option" :["(A) The U.S.A",
               "(B) England",
               "(C) France",
               "(D) None of these"],
    "answer" : "D"
    }
]
